Alger family. Additional papers, 1897-1980 (inclusive), 1918-1980 (bulk): A Finding Aid
Additional papers, 1897-1980 (inclusive), 1918-1980 (bulk)
1632--80-M189
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute
ALGER FAMILY
1.63 linear ft. (1 carton, 1 + 1/2 file boxs)
Addenda to the papers (A-103) of the Alger family from New England, including correspondence, photographs and account books.
Accession numbers: 1632, 1650, 70-8, 70-62, 70-126, 71-27, 73-56, 74-12, 74-67, 74-101, 74-125, 74-178, 75-24, 75-214, 76-203, 77-M213, 78-M110, 79-M111, 80-M189
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Addenda to the papers (A-103) of the Alger family from New England, including correspondence, photographs and account books. There is additional related material at the Schlesinger Library. See Alger family Additional papers, 1809-1984 (inclusive), 1952-1981 (bulk) 84-M102, and Alger family Additional papers, 1919-1982 84-M45. Folders #20-31 for which original restrictions have expired were added to the collection in November 2009.
CONTAINER LIST
Box 1: Folders 1-9
Carton 2: Folders 10-36
Box 3: 37-40
INVENTORY
- Letters to Louisa R. Alger, 1964-1969., 1.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey and Marion Morehouse Cummings, 1947-1952., 2.
- Taylor cup file, correspondence and photographs, 1953-1967., 3.
- Letters to Sally Sprague, ca.1922-1934, diary 1925., 4.
- Diaries, 1897-1956., 5.
- Case of Ronald Cyr, handled by Sally Sprague, 1960-1964., 6.
- South End Music Centre, letters to Sally Sprague, 1960-1964., 7.
- Sally Sprague's papers, including notes for speeches, clippings, 1964-1967., 8.
- Letters to LRA, 1965-1969., 9.
- Letters to LRA, 1970., 10.
- Commission against Discrimination: letters to LRA, and papers, 1969-1970., 11.
- Letters to LRA from the Warren Center and the American Friends Service Committee, 1969-1970., 12.
- Letters to LRA, 1972-1973, and medal., 13.
- Letters to LRA, 1973., 14.
- Abby Langdon Alger (1850-): recipes and commonplace books., 15.
- LRA's account books, 1937, 1959; pamphlet on Roxbury, 1967., 16.
- College themes and Honors thesis, 1918-1922., 17.
- LRA's account books, 1938-1970., 18.
- Letters to LRA and notes for 25th Reunion speech., 19.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey,; E.E. Cummings, and Marion Cummings, 1948-1955., 20.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey,; E.E. Cummings, and Marion Cummings, 1948-1955., 21.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey, 1951-1952., 22.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey, 1953., 23.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey, 1954., 24.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey,; Marion Cummings, 1957., 25.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey, 1962-1965., 26.
- Letters and photographs, 1928-1947., 27.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey and Marion Cummings, 1966-1968., 28.
- Letters from J.L. Sweeney and Jere Knight, 1968-1969., 29.
- Letters from Alcy Frelick, 1975-1976., 30.
- Letters from Elizabeth Cummings Qualey, 1969-1975 and re Marion Cummings., 31.
- Letters from Alcy Frelick, 1976-1977., 32.
- Letters from Alcy Frelick, 1978., 33.
- Letters from Alcy Frelick, 1979., 34.
- Letters to LRA, 1975-1980, 35.
- Letters to LRA re: Warren Center, 1960s-1970s, 36.
- Inquiries to LRA from Collier's Reference Service, 1940-1960s, 37-40.